FFT Software

TUAN NGUYEN HUU

PERSONAL DETAIL

• Name **TUAN NGUYEN HUU**

Nationality Vietnamese

• Sex Male

• Email nguyenhuutuan48@gmail.com

LANGUAGE

• Vietnamese Mother Tongue

• English Fluent

EDUCATION

Period	Institution	Degree
2011 – 2016	Posts and Telecommunications Institute of Technology	Engineer of Information Technology
2017	Oracle Certified Associate JAVA 8 (OCA)	Certificate
2018	Oracle Certified Professional JAVA 8 (OCP)	Certificate
2019	IBM Certificate System Administrator (WebSphere Application Server Network Deployment V9.0)	Certificate

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Period	Company	Title
Jun 2019 - Present	FPT Software	Technical leader, Senior Developer, Developer

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

- Highly skilled IT professional with 5 years professional experience including application development, implementation, deployment, internal and customer support.
- Performed developer/technical leader/team lead role in projects.
- Have consistently contributed to the company's growth and profitability by combining strong technical, management knowledge and with a dedicated proactive approach.
- Cooperative and able to perform within a team-oriented atmosphere

ManagementExperience

Role	Level	Experience	
Technical leader	Medium	2 years	
Developer	High	3 years	
Technical Skill			
Architecture	Level	Experience	
Microservice (Restful)	High	5 years	
Web service (SOAP)	Medium	2 years	
Programming languages	Level	Experience	
Java OOP	High	5 years	
Spring boot	High	4 years	
Spring JPA	High	3 years	
Hibernate	High	3 years	
HTML 5	High	3 years	
CSS 3	High	3 years	
Angular 6,7,8	Medium	2 years	
Java script	Medium	2 years	
Typescript	Medium	2 years	
Unit test (TDD)	High	5 years	
Integration test (BDD)	High	4 years	
Android	Low	1 year	
С	Low	1 year	
C++	Low	1 year	
Database	Level	Experience	
Postgre	High	3 years	
Oracle	Medium	1 year	
Sqlite	Medium	1 year	
Cassandra (No SQL)	High	3 years	
Solr (Search engine)	High	2 years	
Messaging system	Level	Experience	
RabbitMQ	High	2 years	

Cloud	Level	Experience	
AWS	Medium	2 years	
CI/CD	Level	Experience	
Jenkins	High	3 years	
OpenShift (Redhat)	Medium	1 year	
Docker	Medium	2 years	
Caching	Level	Experience	
Redis	High	2 years	
Operating system	Level	Experience	
Windows	High	5 years	
Linux	Medium	2 years	
Ubuntu	Medium	1 years	
Version control	Level	Experience	
SVN	High	2 year	
GIT	High	4 years	
Source Code Analysis	Level	Experience	
Sonarqube	High	3 years	
Checkmarx	High	3 years	
IDE	Level	Experience	
Eclipse	High	5 years	
Visual Studio Code	High	3 years	
IntelliJ	Medium	2 year	
Android Studio	Medium	1 year	
MS visual studio			
M3 visual studio	Medium	1 year	
Tools	Medium Level	1 year Experience	
		, and the second	
Tools	Level	Experience	
Tools Maven	Level High	Experience 5 years	
Tools Maven SoapUI	Level High High	Experience 5 years 2 years	

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

FPT SOFTWARE Aug 2019 – Present

Projects PFW Migration.

Objectives Migrate the Cyber platform to Escalus platform for PFW. Improve the

performance, scalability by using new technologies and new

architecture. Seamlessly transit the current users to new platform.

Taken Role Technical Lead

Responsibility

• Estimate, manage task of team, support member

- Study requirements, create Detail Design
- Review source code
- Optimize code
- Deal with issues arise
- Write detailed design documents for several modules
- Prepare training documents and train new recruits.
- Create technical specifications incorporating user requirements, architecture standards and knowledge of the underlying systems to define solutions which are cost effective and sustainable.
- Support deployment
- Coding
- Unit test (TDD)
- Integration test (BDD)

Technology

- Restful web service
- RabitMQ
- Java OOP, Spring-boot, Spring JPA, Hibernate
- Angular 8, HTML5, CSS3, Java Script, Jquery
- Postgre, Cassandra, Solr (Search engine)
- AWS, Jenkin, Docker, OpenShift (Redhat), Redis
- Swagger, UML
- Redis
- GIT
- Sonarqube, Checkmarx
- Test-driven development (TDD)
- Behavior-driven development (BDD)

FPT SOFTWARE

Dec 2018 - Aug 2019

Projects Zenda

Objectives The shipping solution for global ecommerce. https://zenda.global/

Taken Role Senior Developer

Responsibility

- Coding
- Unit test
- Integration test
- Support team members

Technology

- Restful web service
- Java OOP, Hibernate
- Angular 6, HTML5, CSS3, Java Script, Jquery
- Postgre, Cassandra
- Swagger, UML
- GIT
- Test-driven development (TDD)
- Behavior-driven development (BDD)

FPT SOFTWARE

May 2018 - Dec 2018

Projects FCS

Objectives Based on Escalus, FCS is a shipping system that will enable Neopost

franking customers to access a range of Royal Mail parcel products via an online portal using the franking account as the basis for payment. It is envisaged that this new process will aid development of the Royal Mail parcel products in the franking channel and will offer Neopost customers

a streamlined and efficient way of processing them.

Taken Role Senior Developer

Responsibility

- Coding
- Unit test
- Integration test

Technology

- Restful web service
- Java OOP, Hibernate
- Angular 4, HTML5, CSS3, Java Script, Jquery
- Postgre, Cassandra
- GIT
- Test-driven development (TDD)
- Behavior-driven development (BDD)

Projects Expresslink

Objectives This project is aim to build a logistic system to manage the supply chain

and resources.

Taken Role Developer.

Responsibility

- Coding
- Unit test
- Integration test

Technology

- Restful web service
- Java OOP, JDBC
- HTML5, CSS3, Java Script, Jquery
- Postgre, Cassandra
- SVN
- Test-driven development (TDD)
- Behavior-driven development (BDD)

FPT Software Jun 2016 - Mar 2017

Projects Escalus

Objectives Develop a logistic platform which aims to: Reduces time and cost to

implement new services for customers. Offers great performance. Is easy to maintain, extend and scale. Aggregates and centralizes the different

features/API in the supply chain.

Taken Role Developer.

Responsibility

- Coding
- Unit test
- Integration test

Technology

- Restful web service
- Java 00P
- Postgre, Cassandra, Solr
- SVN
- Test-driven development (TDD)
- Behavior-driven development (BDD)

AWARDS & RECONGITIONS

- Best Performance at BU 2019
- FPT Software Platinum Club 2018, 2019